Ted Key Papers
Ted Key Papers
- Promotional material
  - Movie publicity
    - Showdown at Ulcer Gulch poster, 1956; screenplay by Key (Oversize 55)
  - Pamphlets, 1955-1956; 1966 (Box 37)
    Fatal Fallacies (Travelers insurance)
    Hazel's Household Hints
    Training Can Be Fun (and Useful Too) (Ken-L Products)
  - Posters, 1951; 1977-1978,; 1985; topics include safety and smoking (Oversize 55)
    Lakeside Pharmaceuticals
    New Jersey Department of Law and Public Safety
  - Miscellaneous, 1984; 1990,; 2004 (Oversize 56)
    Big Brothers/Big Sisters of America advertisement
    Hazel advertising campaign material
    Hazel greeting card sample
    South Jersey Gas Company reprints
- Proofs
  - Hazel syndicated cartoon, 1995 (Oversize 56)
    Please note the following omissions:
    1995: missing 1/1-3/4, 7/24-729, 11/20-11/25
  - Hazel syndicated cartoon, 1996-2002; Each year except 1996 contains 2 sets of proofs. (Box 10)
    1996: missing 12/30-12/31
    1998: Set 1- missing 12/7-12/12; Set 2- 3/16-3/21, 12/7-12/12
    1999: Set 2- missing 1/4-1/9, 4/26-5/1
    2002: Set 2- missing 5/21
  - Hazel syndicated cartoon, 2003-2008 (Box 11)
    2007: Set 1 and 2- missing 8/13-8/18, 8/27-9/1, 9/10-9/30, 11/5-11/10, 11/25-12/14
    2008: Set 1 and 2- missing 3/17-3/22, 4/7-4/12, 5/17-12/31
  - Hazel proofs used by Dutton & Co for Hazel book, circa 1947; undated; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Magazine spread proofs, undated (Oversize 55)
  - "Man of the Soil" color proofs, undated (Oversize 56)
  - Negative proof for Saturday Evening Post cartoon, 1954 (Box 17)
- Writings, majority are by Key; Hazel television scripts were written by others
  - Cat from Outer Space
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 27)
    - Outline, 1975 (Box 27)
    - Outline for revised screenplay, 1976 (Box 27)
    - Rough artwork and note, circa 1970s; depicts dogs, note explains original idea to story involve dogs (Box 27)
    - Screenplay- 1st revision, 1976 (Box 27)
    - Screenplay- 1st submission, 1976 (Box 27)
    - Screenplay, 1975; 1976 (Box 28)
    - Screenplay, 1976; 2 versions (Box 28)
    - Screenplay, Jul 14 1976 (Box 38)
    - Screenplay, 1977 (Box 28)
    - Shooting script, 1977; 2 copies (Box 29)
    - Shooting script, Mar 3 1977 (Box 38)
    - Story, 1970s (Box 29)
    - Typescript for book, circa 1977-1978 (Box 29)
  - Digby The Biggest Dog in the World
    - Screenplay, undated; 2 versions (Box 29)
    - Script, 1966; first draft (Box 30)
    - Unidentified, circa 1959 (Box 30)
  - Dolan's Devil
    - A tv comedy series, undated (Box 30)
  - Emma's First National Bank (Jennie's Bank), a tv comedy series
    - Treatment, undated (Box 30)
    - Scripts, 1966 (Box 30)
  - Gus
    - Screenplays, 1974; undated (Box 30)
    - Story, undated; 2 versions (Box 30)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 31)
  - Half a Moustache: a Memoir
    - Part I, 1994 (Box 31)
    - Part II, 1995; 2 copies (Box 31)
    - Part III, 1998 (Box 31)
    - Part IV, 1998 (Box 31)
  - Hazel, several in collaboration with Mark Shaw.
    - Gags for cartoons, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 23)
    - Gags for cartoons, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 24)
    - Gags for cartoons, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 25)
    - Gags for cartoons, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 26)
    - "Hazel Bible", 1960s-1980s; written in 1960, updated in the 1970s and 1980s, used for reference purposes by those producing the Hazel television series (Box 22)
    - Motion picture story, undated (Box 22)
    - Movie outline, 1993 (Box 22)
    - Movie outline, 1993; includes 1 piece of correspondence (Box 22)
    - Movie outline, 1993; second draft (Box 22)
    - Movie screenplay, circa 1990s (Box 33)
    - Movie screenplay, 1993; first draft sent to Mark Shaw (Box 33)
    - Movie screenplays, circa 1990s; 1993; 3 items (Box 33)
    - Movie story board outline, 1993 (Box 33)
    - Musical proposal, undated (Box 34)
    - Musical story outlines, undated; 2 items (Box 34)
    - Musical script, 1984; 2 items (Box 34)
    - Television pilot, 1960 (Box 18)
    - Television prospectus, 1960 (Box 18)
    - Television scripts, 1961-1962; some include multiple drafts, revisions (Box 18)
      3002-3005, 3007, 3414, 3418-3419, 3442, 3499, 3504, 3510, 3514, 3517, 3520, 3604-3607
    - Television scripts, 1962; 1965; some include multiple drafts, revisions (Box 19)
      3607-3617
    - Television scripts, 1962-1963; 1965; some include multiple drafts, revisions (Box 20)
      3618-3625
    - Television scripts, 1963; 1965-1966; some include multiple drafts, revisions (Box 21)
      3627-3639
    - Television scripts, 1963; 1966; some include multiple drafts, revisions (Box 22)
      3640, 3643, 3647-3653, 3656-3659
  - Huggins
    - Screen treatment by Ted Key and Merrill Pannitt, 1991 (Box 31)
  - The Incredible Buffalo Bill
    - Television Series by Ted Key and Merrill Pannitt, 1979 (Box 31)
  - Jim Hill is Pregnant
    - Screen treatment by Ted Key and Merrill Pannitt, 1989 (Box 31)
  - Lily
    - TV format, 1979 (Box 31)
  - Million Dollar Duck (Mr. Webfoot Waddle)
    - Screen story, undated (Box 27)
  - Nessie Come Home with Merrill Pannitt
    - Film story, undated (Box 31)
    - Screenplay "master copy", 1985; 2 copies (Box 32)
    - Screenplays, undated (Box 32)
  - Philadelphia Spring with Maury Cohen
    - Film treatment, undated; 2 copies (Box 32)
    - Outline, 1978; undated; also includes 2 pieces of correspondence (Box 32)
  - Positive Attitude Posters
    - Ideas, undated (Box 12)
  - Rural Delivery
    - Treatment outline, undated (Box 32)
  - Speedway by Ted Key and Maury Cohen, a totally different concept in Television "Quiz" Games!
    - Proposal, undated; includes illustrations (Box 32)
  - The Taming of Joe Huggins with Merrill Pannitt
    - Screen treatment, 1990 (Box 34)
  - Wild WAC Roundup with Merrill Pannitt
    - Screenplay, 1982 (Box 34)
- Miscellaneous
  - Biggest Dog in the World book, 1960; 1981; signed copy; contains letter from Key (Box 37)
  - Cartoonist Profiles No. 78, Jun 1988 (Box 38)
  - Clippings, 1942; 1947,; 1954,; undated; includes copy of the Fort Dix newspaper (Oversize 56)
  - Clippings of Key's cartoons published outside of the U.S., undated (Box 37)
  - Diz and Liz coloring book, 1964 (Box 38)
  - Dummy for If You Like Hazel, circa 1952 (Box 37)
  - Dummy for Me Too (So'MI) children's book, before 1963 (Box 37)
  - Media History Digest Comics and Cartoons Issue, 1985; Vol. 5 No. 4 Fall (Box 37)
  - Toonerviews cassette tape recording, 1991-1992; Ted Key, Chon Day, Fred Lasswell, Hank Ketcham, Chance Brown (Box 38)
  - Translation of the foreword in the Norwegian version of Hazel, undated (Box 37)
  - Writer's Yearbook interview, 1970 (Box 37)